eighteen thousand and seventy Andrew
Holland is with us Chief Executive
Officer of Avengers alternate strategies
he's a market Master of the day Andrew
great to have you with us here thank you
very much for your time
uh higher or lower I mean I think it's
that kind of a binary question because
uh you know the question on lore comes
from the fact that at higher levels
there is consistent selling foreigners
have been sellers uh all through this
year which is all the three weeks or so
and on the upside you know one can also
make the case that there is not really
very much uh wrong with a market per se
uh which which way would you go uh
Andrew I'm talking about the near to
medium term
yeah I know it's uh I I think we um it's
a little bit confusing uh prashem
because um you you've kind of you know
could have nailed that the part where
there's optimism and a bit of pessimism
as well I mean on the on the reopening
of China uh I mean we saw some GDP data
the other day showing uh you know last
year was around three percent and the
last quarter was around 2.7 if I
remember correctly
um and that's you know do you you know
those figures are you know despite the
kind of you know the the shutdowns that
they have
um so obviously now the expectation is
that you know growth will recover very
quickly
um and there'll be a lot of spending by
consumers as they you know managed to
get out as we've seen you know elsewhere
in the world and and here in India too
so that GDP growth could be narrowed to
five percent this year
um therefore it's a cheap market and uh
you know whilst uh we were all talking
last year about how China is not so good
and India's you know shining because of
that um you know that reverse of
thinking is on the way and that's why
we're seeing more flows go towards China
some taken out of India because of that
so
um you know that's that's obviously you
know hitting what the fiis are thinking
in terms of their views on India in the
shorter term which is putting the
pressure on on the selling
um on the upside
um you know you're good in markets which
are are being supported globally and you
know one of the things which is uh I'm
trying to work through Prashant is I'm
sure you're heard him from Davos too all
the people saying it's going to be
recession globally and we're not against
that but if I look at the data coming
out of Europe where there's been a
actually a very mild winter and there's
uh in fact you know supplies are you
know more than adequate now and if I
look at the UK where you know retail
sales in the over Christmas was very
strong house prices actually Rose over
the past month
um you know what if what if we're wrong
what if what is not a a global recession
and actually it's it's really just a
mild slowdown what does that mean in
terms of growth and I think that's what
the Market's liking that part of it in
in terms of the growth which is pushing
up European markets as well as the as
well as the US
um but that you know when you look
forward on that you're going to have
probably higher commodity prices because
of China opening
um and um you'll probably have the FED
being you know staying a little bit
longer than we would expect so I think
those are going to be the push-pull
factors in in terms of the markets over
the next few few months and um I think
we're going to just be in a bit of a
trading range unfortunately
all right we're going to be in a trading
range by the way just a couple of more
details on ICICI Lombard that's actually
the big loser in the broader markets
down almost five percent uh now of
course we do know that the premium
growth was on the weaker side this time
the investment income was lower and that
dragged the profit growth for the
company but uh you know motilal oswal
has put out a note where they put out
some highlights from the management
commentary and the commentary is also on
the weaker side where they mentioned
that the competitive intensity remains
very high especially in the motor
segment and that's due to the passenger
car category so I say I say a Lombard
not just numbers are weak but commentary
is also quite cautious Andrew hi good
morning how are you feeling about India
now do you think this resilience that
we've seen all of last year the out
performance is something that can
continue and you know how are you
positioned what's the asset allocation
strategy within India in 2023
well in fact we're more constructive
about markets globally going into this
year yes there could be you know we've
we think when we spoke last time there's
been a bottoming out process we think
that might continue
um if I've just you know correcting what
I'm saying that you know the global
economy you know is not as bad as uh
maybe we were expecting then obviously
you know there might be thoughts around
stagflation at some point uh over the
next quarter so I still think Leo
there's some there's some downside to
markets
um you know uh in in in in the shorter
term but I think once the FED goes on
hold then I think the whole play on
emerging markets and growth will will
continue to
um to come to a lot stronger
um I do think though that there's
cheaper markets out there than than
India and I think that will uh probably
have at least for the first half whilst
we might rise because we'll get flows
um I think the flows will go to other
countries as we've been seeing in like
career in China and Taiwan uh over the
past over the past few months
um so we might underperform uh but it
doesn't necessarily mean that we'll go
down as a market unless Global markets
take a hit because of of worries over
you know many different things including
stipulation
hi Andrew well so you know after a good
2022 maybe some bit of consolidation uh
maybe flows you know go to other cheaper
markets worst case scenario what does
Nifty go down to
no so I'm it depends on obviously you
know what uh what the global markets
kind of moved to but I think whichever
way I look at it you know if the markets
fall five ten percent globally then I
think we'd be half of that
um I think the resilience is still there
so unless there's any shops in the
budget which we're not expecting
um then you know we'll continue to to
grind higher over a longer period And I
think you know if I was to think of
where Nifty might be in terms of from
where we are today if it follows in line
with earnings growth which we're
expecting anywhere between 10 to 15
growth and I think that's probably where
we'll end up by the end of the year
Andrew uh give us some sort of broad
ways to think about trading ideas
uh at this point because I'm assuming
that you don't have a firm conviction of
which way the market heads so uh you you
trade around and you can do that in the
fund so just give us a sense of what
you're doing or what you want to do in
an environment like this
so I think I I think appreciate what you
have to think about is is the very near
term and what uh and what what are the
catalysts
um and I think the catalyst is obviously
going to be you know a Fed going on hold
and when you think that will be we think
it's going to be in the first quarter uh
of of this calendar year so if that's
the case then I would think that you
know growth stocks in the U.S or tech
stocks in the US will probably have a
push higher from where we are today I'm
not saying that some of the individual
stocks might now have problems
um but I think tech stocks in in by and
large will move higher and I think
that's probably the Tailwind RIT stocks
need
um you know to to to to push higher uh
over the first quarter and I think
that's what uh so if I'm thinking about
the kind of Trades and that's a trade I
would want to uh to be on the long side
uh and and alongside that would
obviously be the reopening of China and
we're already starting to see commodity
prices
starting to rise and obviously unless
we'll as we've seen today will start
upgrading forecasts
um you know for for the metal pack uh
going forward as well so those are are
two kind of long long trades and they're
probably just offset that with a with
maybe kind of you know thinking about
where I would want to to short and
obviously higher commodity prices are
going to lead to
um you know sectors like paints and
Autos again being under pressure in the
very short term
all right so you're saying that go long
on the I.T stocks right in India
I'm saying if that's the view of you of
my view is that that's what's gonna you
know the fed's gonna play out and that's
a more shorter term trade yeah
okay that's a shorter term trade got it
the other space I wanted to talk to you
about was Private capex you know we just
had a note that we put out from Bank of
America's buffer Securities where they
mentioned that government capex had
picked up up until now but this is going
to be the Europe and private kpex picks
up in a big way because the government
is opening up a lot of monopolies to
attract both private as well as
Government capex if that is the case uh
who do you see as the big beneficiaries
will it be cement stocks will it be
infrastructure names lnt is at a record
high as well how do you play this theme
it's something we talked about uh Sonia
for most of last year with you in that
um you know we we do expect the global
recovery to be from you know a global
capex cycle picking up
um and there's two areas which are
definitely going to you know receive a
lot of uh expenditure both from
government and private uh companies is
going to be Renewables and defense so
those two you know are going to play out
throughout uh you know the many years uh
in terms of the kind of normal kind of
capex yes you're going to have the
government spending on Rose Bridges and
so forth but I think it's the um it's
the areas where there's been a security
problem in terms of Supply where you're
going to see a lot more manufacturing uh
come into India and that lends itself to
you know other parts of uh of the kind
of um
um you know industrial kind of
Industrials so the kind of Siemens the
abbs of this world I think we'll do it
we'll Garner more contracts going
forward and I think you've seen that uh
in terms of the you know the share
prices uh rising over the past year
result I think that will continue so I
think it's a it's a it's it's good that
there's there's a lot of uh capex coming
from the private companies and I think
the pli is going to help and I just
looking through some stats
um in that uh whilst exports are falling
uh electronics are picking up and I
think that's going to be a big big area
for India if they can if they can grab
the opportunity and electronics going
forward not just
um you know to beat the domestic demand
but also for exports going forward so I
think that's going to be a big theme so
whilst you know I'm saying that the the
index might not might be in a short-term
trading range I think there's going to
be the themes that play out this year
and that's where you're going to make
the big money
okay well thanks a lot for joining in
Andrew have a great 2023 we'll keep
chatting with you through the course of
the year but thanks for joining us on
the channel today well moving